Guide to the First Congregational Church of Portland records 1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Newsletters, 1891-2015; Series R
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 25, 1953 September 6 - 1954 August 29 (Box-folder 86/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 26, 1954 September 5 - 1955 August 28 (Box-folder 86/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 27, 1955 September 3 - 1956 August 26 (Box-folder 86/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 28, 1956 September 2 - 1957 August 25 (Box-folder 86/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 29, 1957 September 8 - 1958 August 31 (Box-folder 87/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 30, 1958 September 7 - 1959 August 30 (Box-folder 87/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 30-31, 1959 (Box-folder 87/3)
    Combined single volume. Many of the issues not in chronological order.
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 31, 1959 September 6 - 1960 August 28 (Box-folder 87/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 32, 1960 September 4 - 1961 August 30 (Box-folder 88/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 33, 1961 September 7 - 1962 August 26 (Box-folder 88/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 34, 1962 September 2 - 1963 August 29 (Box-folder 88/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 35-36, 1964 January 2 - 1965 December 28 (Box-folder 88/4)
    Issues of "The Pilgrim" from this folder on are unbound.
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 37-38, 1966 January 5 - 1967 September 19 (Box-folder 88/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 39-40, 1967 September 26 - 1969 February 25 (Box-folder 89/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 41-42, 1969 March 4 - 1970 December 29 (Box-folder 89/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 43-44, 1971 January 5 - 1972 December 26 (Box-folder 89/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 45-46, 1973 January 2 - 1974 December 23 (Box-folder 89/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 47-48, 1975 January 6 - 1976 December 28 (Box-folder 89/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 49, 1977 January 4 - June (Box-folder 89/6)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 49, 1977 July - December 27 (Box-folder 89/7)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 50, 1978 January 3 May 23 (Box-folder 89/8)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 50, 1978 June - December 26 (Box-folder 90/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 51, 1979 January 2 - May 29 (Box-folder 90/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 51, 1979 July - December 18 (Box-folder 90/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 52, 1980 January 1 - May 20 (Box-folder 90/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 52, 1980 June - December 29 (Box-folder 90/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 53, 1981 January 6 - July (Box-folder 90/6)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 53, 1981 August - December 21 (Box-folder 90/7)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 54, 1982 January 4 - May 24 (Box-folder 90/8)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 54, 1982 May - December 20 (Box-folder 90/9)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 55, 1983 January 3 - May 23 (Box-folder 91/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 55, 1983 June - December (Box-folder 91/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 56, 1984 January 3 - June (Box-folder 91/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 56, 1984 July - December (Box-folder 91/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 57, 1985 January 7 - June (Box-folder 91/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 57, 1985 July - December 30 (Box-folder 91/6)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 58, 1986 January 6 - March 31 (Box-folder 91/7)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 59/"Update!" Volume 1, 1986 April-December (Box-folder 91/8)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 60/"Update!" Volume 1, 1987 January-March (Box-folder 92/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 60-61, 1987 March 12 - August 26 (Box-folder 92/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 62, 1987 September 6 - 1988 August 28 (Box-folder 92/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volume 63, 1988 September 4 - 1989 December 31 (Box-folder 92/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 64-65, 1990 January 14 - 1991 December 15 (Box-folder 92/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 66-68, 1992 January 5 - 1994 March 27 (Box-folder 92/6)
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 1994 April 17 - December 25 (Box-folder 92/7)
    Issues from April 1994 to 2001 did not have volume numbers.
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 1996 January 14 - 1997 December 15 (Box-folder 93/1)
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 1998 January 1 - December 15 (Box-folder 93/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 1999 January 17 - December 1 (Box-folder 93/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 2000 January 1 - December 1 (Box-folder 93/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" issues, 2001 January 1 - December 1 (Box-folder 93/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 1-2, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 93/6)
    Issues resumed having volume numbers in 2002, but started over at "1."
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 3-4, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 94/1)
    Issue for March 2005 is missing.
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 5-6, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 94/2)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 7-8, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 94/3)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 9-11, 2010-2011 (Box-folder 94/4)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 12-13, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 94/5)
  - "The Pilgrim" Volumes 14-15, 2014-2015 (Box-folder 94/6)
  - Outside newsletters, Subseries 1
    - "Home Missionary", 1891 October (Box-folder 76/14)
    - "The Advance" issues, 1897 (Box-folder 112/22)
    - Page from "The Congregationalist and Christian World", circa 1912 (Box-folder 112/23)
      Page shows regional officers of National Federation of Woman's State Home Missionary Organizations, including Elizabeth Eggert.
    - "The Congregationalist" issues, 1899 September (Box-folder 112/24)
    - "The Congregationalist" issues, 1899 October-November (Box-folder 112/25)
    - "The Congregationalist" issue, 1925 June 25 (Box-folder 113/22)
    - "The Congregationalist and Advance" issues, 1920 (Box-folder 113/23)
    - "The Congregationalist and Christian World" issues, 1910; 1915 (Box-folder 113/24)
    - "The Missionary Herald", 1936 March (Box-folder 76/15)
      Includes an article about George H. Himes, written by Reverend Raymond Walker.
    - "Oregon Congregationalist" issues, 1955 (Box-folder 112/26)
    - "Oregon United Church News" issues, 1964; 1968; 1970 (Box-folder 76/16)
    - "The Pacific", 1910 October (Box-folder 76/17)
    - "Woman's Board of Mission for the Pacific Monthly Bulletin" issues, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 112/27)
      January 1923 issue includes an article by Frances Clapp.
- Publicity, 1930-2014; Series S
  - Branding template, 2014 July (Box-folder 95/1)
  - Memos and press releases re advertisements and media coverage, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 95/2)
  - Brochures and other promotional handouts, 1930-1970 (Box-folder 95/3-95/4)
  - Brochures and other promotional handouts, 1980-2010 (Box-folder 95/5-95/6)
  - Brochure - "Memorials and History", 1959 (Box-folder 95/7)
    Written by Mary Gray.
  - Brochure - "History and Memorials", 1966 (Box-folder 95/8)
    Written by Mary Gray and Lena Little.
  - Correspondence - Letters of appreciation for advertisements, 1980; 1983 (Box-folder 95/9)
  - Newspaper articles, photographs, and advertisements, 1932-2008 (Box-folder 95/10)
  - Correspondence, records, and ephemera re radio broadcasts of sermons, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 95/11)
- Interchurch and interfaith activities, 1903-2006; Series T
  - Interfaith activities - general, 1944-2004 (Box-folder 95/12)
  - Certificate of Remembrance from Bielefeld-Ubbedissen Kirche, Germany, 1989 October (Box-folder 95/13)
  - Illustration of Evangelische Kirche Ubbedissen with sheet music of hymn by Pachelbel, circa 1989 (Box-folder 113/21)
  - Materials relating to other Congregational churches, circa 1910-1954, undated (Box-folder 95/14)
  - Ecumenical Ministries, 1985-2006 (Box-folder 95/15)
  - First Christian Church, 1945-2002 (Box-folder 95/16)
  - Five Downtown Churches, 1947-2001 (Box-folder 96/1)
  - Greater Portland Council of Churches, 1928-1983 (Box-folder 96/2)
  - Portland Association of Congregational Churches, 1903-1970 (Box-folder 96/3)
  - Correspondence with Tsukisappu Church, Sapporo, Japan, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 96/4)
  - Pamphlets and ephemera from Tsukisappu Church, 1965 (Box-folder 96/5)
    Materials are in Japanese.
- Conferences and conventions, 1884-2012; Series U
  - Research files (Box-folder 96/6)
  - Certificates for persons chosen as delegates to State Association meeting, 1880 June 10 (Box-folder 96/7)
    Certificates written by George H. Himes.
  - Minutes of the Congregational Association of Oregon and Washington, 1884 July (Box-folder 96/8)
  - Materials and ephemera re regional and national conferences, 1889-1911 (Box-folder 96/9)
  - National Council of Congregational Churches sermon, "Freedom and Mediation", 1898 (Box-folder 96/10)
  - Correspondence and records re National Council dues, 1898-1901 (Box-folder 96/11)
  - Documents and research files re gavel presented at Pacific Coast Congress of Congregational Churches, 1911, undated (Box-folder 96/12)
  - Correspondence re delegates to National Council, 1921 May-June (Box-folder 96/13)
  - Letter from Oregon Conference of United Church of Christ suggesting OCWM fundraising goal, 1970 September 18 (Box-folder 96/14)
  - Regional conferences, 1915-1920 (Box-folder 96/15)
  - Regional conferences, 1944-1955 (Box-folder 96/16)
  - Regional conferences, 1964-1992 (Box-folder 96/17)
  - Regional conferences - Pacific Central Conference, 1984-2012 (Box-folder 97/1)
  - Reports of the Congregational Conference of Oregon for 1929, 1930 (Box-folder 97/2)
- Images, 1857-2013; Series V
  Primarily photographs.
  Access to negatives, plate images, and daguerreotype is restricted.
  - Album, 1996-1999 (Box-folder Box 149)
  - Album, 1997-1999 (Box-folder Box 150)
  - Album, 1999-2000 (Box-folder Box 152)
  - Church exterior, Subseries 1
    Subseries does not include drawn and painted illustrations or postcards.
    - Exterior of second church building, circa 1875 (Box-folder 99/1, 113/6)
    - Glass negative of third church building exterior, circa 1895 (Box-folder 156/1)
      Access to this item is restricted.
    - Exterior of third church building, circa 1895-1935 (Box-folder 99/2)
    - Third church building exterior, 1922 June (Box-folder 99/3)
      Images previously removed from an album.
    - Exterior of third church building, circa 1940-1960 (Box-folder 99/4)
    - Lincoln statue and third church building exterior, circa 1950 (Box-folder 113/7)
    - Safety negative of third church building exterior, circa 1945 (Box-folder 156/8)
    - Snapshots of third church building exterior, 1960 June (Box-folder 99/5)
    - Exterior of third church building, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 99/6)
    - Exterior of third church building, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 99/7)
    - Exterior of third church building, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 99/8)
  - Church interior, Subseries 2
    - General interior views, 1975-2012 (Box-folder 99/9)
    - Adult Lounge, 1950 July 19 (Box-folder 99/10)
    - Altar of Remembrance, circa 1944 (Box-folder 99/11)
      Includes explanatory caption card.
    - Assembly Room, circa 1950 (Box-folder 99/12)
    - Basement, circa 1945 (Box-folder 99/13)
    - Printing plate image of basement, circa 1948 (Box-folder 156/2)
    - Printing plate image of basement, circa 1951 (Box-folder 156/3)
    - Chapel, circa 1955 (Box-folder 99/14)
    - Printing plate image of chapel, circa 1952 (Box-folder 156/4)
    - Dossal cloth, undated (Box-folder 99/15)
    - Fellowship Hall, circa 1950 (Box-folder 99/16)
    - View through doorway and of Historical Niche, circa 1960 (Box-folder 99/17)
    - Historical Niche displays, 1991-1995, undated (Box-folder 99/18)
    - Kitchen, 1950 (Box-folder 99/19)
    - Lower level, circa 1951 (Box-folder 99/20)
    - Painting "The French Florals" by Jean Baptiste Mannoyer, circa 1985 (Box-folder 99/21)
      Painting dates from 17th century.
    - Sanctuary decorated for Lee Clark's wedding, 1895 April 17 (Box-folder 99/22)
    - Sanctuary, circa 1896 (Box-folder 99/23)
    - Sanctuary, 1910 (Box-folder 99/24)
    - Sanctuary decorated for Christian Endeavor Sunday, circa 1925 (Box-folder 99/25)
    - Sanctuary, 1931 (Box-folder 99/26)
    - Sanctuary, circa 1935 (Box-folder 99/27)
    - Sanctuary, circa 1945 (Box-folder 99/28)
    - Sanctuary, circa 1955 (Box-folder 99/29)
    - Sanctuary, circa 1980 (Box-folder 99/30)
    - Printing plate image of sanctuary, circa 1955 (Box-folder 156/5)
  - Construction of Portland Performing Arts Center, Subseries 3
    - Performing Arts Center construction, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 99/31)
    - Performing Arts Center construction, 1985 June 4-22 (Box-folder 99/32)
    - Church interior during construction, circa 1985 (Box-folder 99/33)
    - Church interior during construction (negatives), circa 1985 (Box-folder 156/10)
      Access to negatives is restricted.
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund, 1985 March 15 (Box-folder 99/34)
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund, 1985 March 18 (Box-folder 99/35)
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund, 1985 March 19 (Box-folder 100/1)
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund, 1985 April 2 (Box-folder 100/2)
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund; letter from Westerlund to First Congregational Church, 1985 May 15; 1985 May 27 (Box-folder 100/3)
    - Photos by F. J. Westerlund; related documents, 1985 July 3; 1985 July 16 (Box-folder 100/4)
  - Pillar replacement project photographs, 1994; Subseries 4
    - First arch and columns, prior to work (Box-folder 100/5)
    - Second arch and column, prior to work (Box-folder 100/6)
    - Third arch and column, prior to work (Box-folder 100/7)
    - Fourth arch and column against wall, prior to work (Box-folder 100/8)
    - Architectural reproductions/Making molds (Box-folder 100/9)
    - Pumping jacks (Box-folder 100/10)
    - Putting in metal arches (Box-folder 100/11)
    - Cutting columns (Box-folder 100/12)
    - Removing columns and bases (Box-folder 100/13)
    - Drilling holes through columns (Box-folder 100/14)
    - "Tearing Down" (column replacement, removal of metal arches) (Box-folder 100/15)
    - Coring and cutting (Box-folder 101/1)
    - Work on capitals and column bases (Box-folder 101/2)
    - Sidewalk breakup (Box-folder 101/3)
    - New sidewalk installation (Box-folder 101/4)
    - Patching cement, fixing columns (Box-folder 101/5)
    - Finish on sidewalks and columns (Box-folder 101/6)
    - Faux detailing (Box-folder 101/7)
    - Uncategorized photos (Box-folder 101/8)
  - Bell tower repairs, 1991 (Box-folder 101/9)
  - Bell tower repairs, 2003 (Box-folder 101/10)
  - New church school classrooms, 1989 March 21 (Box-folder 101/11)
  - Damage from Columbus Day Storm, 1962 October (Box-folder 101/12)
  - Drawing of First Congregational Church by "Scarey Larry", undated (Box-folder Oversize 47)
  - Greeting cards depicting church windows, 1996; undated (Box-folder 101/13)
  - Illustration depicting first church building, undated (Box-folder 113/5)
  - Illustration by Mel Vincent down SW Madison Street, with First Congregational Church at left, 1975 (Box-folder 113/3)
  - Illustration by John Waddingham depicting view towards First Congregational Church from SW Broadway and SW Jefferson, 1977 (Box-folder 113/4)
  - Interior after flooding, 1990 June (Box-folder 101/14)
  - Kitchen remodel, 1996 February 29 (Box-folder 101/15)
  - Painting of First Congregational Church by Norma Schneider, circa 1985 (Box-folder 101/16)
  - Parsonage, 1955 (Box-folder 101/17)
  - Postcards, circa 1900-1915 (Box-folder 101/18)
  - Postcard, circa 1970 (Box-folder 101/19)
  - Postcard, circa 1990 (Box-folder 101/20)
  - Postcards, 1996-2003 (Box-folder 101/21)
  - Renovations, 1986 (Box-folder 102/1)
  - Renovations, 1987 (Box-folder 102/2)
  - Sanctuary remodel, 2004 (Box-folder 102/3)
  - Tower removal, 1951 October 8 (Box-folder 102/4)
  - Transparencies, circa 1975; undated (Box-folder 156/6)
    Contains transparency copies of photographs and illustrations showing the church exterior.
    Access to folder is restricted.
  - Ministers, etc., Subseries 5
    - Ministers and spouses, 1851-1900 (Box-folder 102/5)
      Includes Peasley Chamberlain and his wife, George Atkinson and his wife, Frederic Marvin, Arthur W. Ackerman and his wife, and George R. Wallace.
    - Copy negatives of portrait of Reverend Peasley Chamberlain and wife (Box-folder 156/7)
    - Ministers, 1902-1923 (Box-folder 102/6)
      Includes Elwin L. House, Luther R. Dyott, and William T. McElveen.
    - Reverend Raymond Walker and choir, circa 1935 (Box-folder 113/9)
    - Ministers, 1929-1959 (Box-folder 102/7)
      Includes Raymond B. Walker, Delia Evans, Charles Harlow, and Ruth McClun.
    - Group photo taken at Reverend Royald V. Caldwell's installation service, 1960 (Box-folder 113/8)
    - Ministers, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 102/8)
      Includes Royald V. Caldwell, Quinn Hawley, John Randlett, Anne Pearse Smith, and Marshall Winfiel.
    - Ministers, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 102/9)
      Includes Lincoln Y. Reed, David Madsen, Mary Olney, Don Rowland, and R'Dean Smith.
    - Ministers, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 102/10)
      Includes John Rogers and Patricia Ross.
    - Reverend Trudy Bradley, circa 2011 (Box-folder 102/11)
    - Staff, circa 1940-1980 (Box-folder 102/12)
  - Members, Subseries 6
    - A-B, 1867-circa 1975 (Box-folder 102/13)
    - C-E, circa 1885-1984 (Box-folder 102/14-102/15)
    - Portrait of "Mrs. Close", circa 1910 (Box-folder 113/18)
    - Dysart family, circa 1920-1934 (Box-folder 102/16)
    - F-H, 1889-2001 (Box-folder 103/1-103/2)
    - Howard, General Oliver O. and family, 1876 (Box-folder 103/3)
    - I-K, circa 1895-1985 (Box-folder 103/4)
    - Kellogg, Edwin D. and Alice, 1909, 1953 (Box-folder 103/5)
    - L-M, circa 1895-1985 (Box-folder 103/6-103/7)
    - N-R, 1867-circa 1965 (Box-folder 103/8-103/9)
    - Oliver, Helen, 1924-1965 (Box-folder 103/10)
    - S-V, 1865-circa 2000 (Box-folder 103/11-103/12)
    - Taylor, Peter and family, 1858 (Box-folder 103/13)
      Copy of original made in 1953.
    - W-Z, circa 1865-1985 (Box-folder 104/1)
    - Unidentified woman, circa 1910 (Box-folder 104/2)
    - Album of new members, 1974-1977 (Box-folder Box 139)
    - Album of members, 1987-1989 (Box-folder Box 153)
    - Group of church members including Frances E. Clapp (Box-folder 104/3)
    - Group of women including Helen Oliver and Carol Buttery, circa 1960 (Box-folder 104/4)
    - Album page showing groups of members, circa 1920 (Box-folder 104/5)
    - Groups of members, 1885-1920 (Box-folder 104/6)
    - Groups of members, circa 1935-1975 (Box-folder 104/7-104/8)
    - Members - "Our Departed Angels", circa 1997 (Box-folder 104/9)
  - Church groups, Subseries 7
    - 35 Year Club party, 1932 May (Box-folder 104/10)
      Includes explanatory caption card and roster of members.
    - 35 Year Club members, circa 1946 (Box-folder 104/11)
    - Church Book Group at Wells residence, 1989 July 11 (Box-folder 104/12)
    - Business and Professional Women's Club group photo, 1950 March 10 (Box-folder 104/13)
    - Camera Club album, 1952-1974 (Box-folder 105/1)
    - Christian Endeavor Halloween party, 1926 (Box-folder 113/11)
    - Christian Endeavor reunion, 1960 July 7 (Box-folder 104/14)
    - Pilgrim Hi styleshow, 1956 (Box-folder 104/15)
    - Pilgrim Hi Fellowship at Suttle Lake, 1963 (Box-folder 104/16)
    - Scrooby Club album, 1959-1963 (Box-folder Box 154)
    - Scrooby club dinner, circa 1955 (Box-folder 104/17)
    - Scrooby Club events, circa 1945-1965 (Box-folder 104/18-104/19)
    - Scrooby Club event, 1958 October (Box-folder 104/20)
    - Scrooby Club events, 1965-circa 1980 (Box-folder 104/21)
    - Scrooby Club group photos, circa 1950 (Box-folder 104/22)
    - Scrooby Club meeting, 1954 June (Box-folder 104/23)
    - Scrooby Club New Year's Party, circa 1945 (Box-folder 106/1)
      Photos by Win Wells.
    - Scrooby Club New Year's Party, circa 1955 (Box-folder 106/2)
    - Scrooby Club officers with Ruth Walker, circa 1955 (Box-folder 106/3)
    - Scrooby Club picnic at Ariel Dam, Washington, 1954 July (Box-folder 106/4)
    - Scrooby Club picnic, 1954 (Box-folder 106/5)
    - Scrooby Club picnic, circa 1955 (Box-folder 106/6)
    - Scrooby Club rummage sale, 1957 (Box-folder 106/7)
    - Senior Adults, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Senior Adult gathering at Higgins residence, 1970 (Box-folder 106/9)
      Also includes roster and explanatory note.
    - Sewing Circle, circa 1955-1965 (Box-folder 106/10)
    - Women's Association picnic at Laurelhurst Park, circa 1925 (Box-folder 113/12)
    - Women's Fellowship bazaars, 1953-1955; undated (Box-folder 106/11)
    - Women's Fellowship bazaar, 1954 November (Box-folder 113/13)
    - Women's groups, 1939-1992 (Box-folder 106/12)
    - Women's groups outings, 1908; circa 1916 (Box-folder 106/13)
  - Adult Sunday School, Subseries 8
    - Church school adult outings, circa 1910-1925 (Box-folder 106/14)
    - Adult Sunday School class pictures, 1925 (Box-folder 106/15)
      Also includes rosters.
    - Adult class in chapel, circa 1990 (Box-folder 106/16)
    - Adult students at Oliver lecture, 2005 (Box-folder 106/17)
    - Charlie Hinkle's Bible class study, circa 1990 (Box-folder 106/18)
  - Sunday School and youth groups, Subseries 9
    - Sunday School album, circa 1925 (Box-folder Box 151)
    - Sunday School children album page, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 106/19)
    - Sunday School children, 1915-circa 1935 (Box-folder 106/20)
    - Sunday School children, 1951-1959 (Box-folder 106/21-106/22)
    - Sunday School youth, circa 1955 (Box-folder 106/23)
    - Sunday School youth, 1961 (Box-folder 106/24)
    - Sunday School children, 1965 (Box-folder 106/25)
    - Sunday School children, circa 1965 (Box-folder 106/26)
    - Sunday School children, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 106/27)
    - Sunday School youth, 1969 October - 1970 January (Box-folder 106/28)
    - Sunday School children, 1972 October (Box-folder 106/29)
    - Sunday School children, circa 1980 (Box-folder 106/30)
    - Sunday School children, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 106/31)
    - Sunday School children, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 106/32)
    - Camp Adams outings, 1954, 1972, undated (Box-folder 106/33)
    - Christian Education youth collage, 1968 (Box-folder 107/1)
    - Sunday School children and youth making Christmas decorations in Fellowship Hall, 1953 (Box-folder 107/2)
    - Sunday School class, 1896 (Box-folder 107/3)
    - Sunday School class, circa 1945 (Box-folder 107/4)
    - Sunday School classrooms, circa 1955 (Box-folder 107/5)
    - Sunday School class photos, circa 1960 (Box-folder 113/14)
    - Sunday School students in Easter dress, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 107/6)
    - Sunday School children on Easter Sunday, 2001 (Box-folder 107/7)
    - Ecumenical School, 1993 March (Box-folder 107/8)
    - "Family Affair" party, 1972 May 21 (Box-folder 107/9)
    - "Free Babysitting", 2004 December 11 (Box-folder 107/10)
    - Holy Week youth events with Cinnamon the Donkey, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 107/11)
    - Heifer project, 1968 March (Box-folder 107/12)
    - "Installation Party at Claries", circa 1972 (Box-folder 107/13)
    - Church youth working at migrant camp, circa 1962 (Box-folder 107/14)
    - Church youth making popcorn and candy, circa 1955 (Box-folder 107/15)
    - Church youth with respirator donated to Spirit Lake camps, 1958 April (Box-folder 107/16)
    - Sunday School teacher Ida May Stauffer, circa 1925 (Box-folder 107/17)
    - Storytime with Reverend Paul Davis, 2004 (Box-folder 107/18)
    - Youth bowling, 2005 (Box-folder 107/19)
  - Music, Subseries 10
    - Group photo of church's first organized choir, 1857 (Box-folder Box 157)
      Original daguerreotype.
      Access to daguerreotype is restricted.
    - Group photo of church's first organized choir, 1857 (Box-folder 107/20)
      Prints made at later dates based on original daguerreotype. Also includes explanatory texts.
    - Choir and other singing groups, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 107/21)
    - Choir at performance of Haydn's "The Creator", 1937 February 14 (Box-folder 113/15)
    - Choir and other singing groups, circa 1965-1999 (Box-folder 107/22)
    - Choir Easter breakfast, circa 1978 (Box-folder 107/23)
    - "Messiah" chorus of choirs, 1935 December 29 (Box-folder 107/24)
    - Organ and organists, 1945-1977 (Box-folder 107/25)